Guide to the Four Seasons Restaurant Collection 1959-2019 MS 3151
New-York Historical Society
- Series V. Books, pamphlets, and periodicals, 1971-2016, undated
  - Martha Stewart. Weddings, 1987 (Offsite-box 10, Volume 3)
    Autographed on front flyleaf: "For everyone at the Four Seasons, Happiness, Best Wishes and Joy! Martha Stewart."
  - Gersil N. Kay. Fiber Optics in Architectural Lighting: Methods, Design, and Applications, 1999 (Offsite-box 10, Volume 4)
  - Dunbar Fine Furniture of the 1950s, 2000 (Offsite-box 10, Volume 5)
  - Leslie McGuirk and Alex von Bidder. Wiggens Learns His Manners at the Four Seasons Restaurant, 2009 (Offsite-box 10, Volume 6)
    Children's picture book about a puppy's introduction to good manners at the Four Seasons, co-written by restaurant owner Alex von Bidder.
  - Ron and Kristine Guialdo. The Color of Magic Event Design, 2011 (Offsite-box 10, Volume 7)
  - The Four Seasons Without Rothko: Completing a Landmark Modernist Interior, 2011 (Offsite-box 10, Volume 8)
  - The Four Seasons [Wright auction catalog, July 26, 2016] (2 copies) (Offsite-box 10, Volume 9)
  - [Wright Auctions] The Four Seasons: The Iconic Interior by Ludwig Mies van der Rohe & Philip Johnson. Proposal for sale., 2016 (Offsite-box 10, Volume 10)
  - Levy Lighting | NYC @ The Four Seasons Restaurant, undated (Offsite-box 10, Volume 11)
  - [Photobook. Julie Skarratt Photography, Inc.], undated (Offsite-box 10, Volume 12)
  - [Photobook. Allan Zepeda Photography], undated (Offsite-box 10, Volume 13)
  - Poi Ti Spiego... The Recipe Booklet of the Four Seasons Restaurant, New York @ Bloomingdale's, undated (Offsite-box 10, Volume 14)
    Water damage has caused the pages of this booklet to stick together, rendering the whole mostly unusable. January 29, 2020.
- Series VI. Audiovisual, 1990-2012, undated
  VHS cassettes, CDs, and DVDs, with footage and still images of the Four Seasons staff being profiled by various news outlets (CNN, Charlie Rose), weddings held at the restaurant, and television programs (both reality and scripted) filmed in its Pool Room, such as Bravo TV's "Bethenny Getting Married?" and the short-lived CBS soap "Central Park West."
  Divided by format -- VHS cassettes and CDs/DVDs -- and organized chronologically.
  - Sub-series VI.A. VHS (31 cassettes), 1990-2000, undated
    Restricted
    The VHS cassettes in Series VI are restricted because of their fragility and because N-YHS has no equipment on which to play them. For further information please contact the curator of manuscripts at manuscripts@nyhistory.org.
    - Financial News Network: Four Seasons segments from "The American Entrepreneur", 1990 October 22 & 23 (Offsite-box 11)
    - Rolling Stone 25th Anniversary Comp Reel, 1992 (Offsite-box 11)
    - Food Network: Food News & Views, 1995 May 1 (Offsite-box 11)
    - NY1 News: Four Seasons, 1995 July 26 (Offsite-box 11)
    - Food Network: Food News & Views Interview with Christian Albin, 1995 October 29 (Offsite-box 11)
    - CBS: Four Seasons / Hitsch, sea urchin, 1996 February 28 (Offsite-box 11)
    - Power Lunch, 1996 May 14 (Offsite-box 11)
    - E T [Entertainment Tonight?] story on Central Park West. Pool Fight, 1996 (Offsite-box 11)
    - CBS: Central Park West, 1996 June 28 (Offsite-box 11)
    - Pat Bullard Show, Segments 4 & 5, [1996 November 8?] (Offsite-box 11)
    - Where New York: In Food Today, 1997 March 31 (Offsite-box 11)
    - Excerpt, Four Seasons Restaurant, from "A Taste of the Nation N.Y.", 1997 April 28 (Offsite-box 11)
    - Biz Buzz, Cable New Network: "Gourmet / Best Restaurants", 1997 November 27 (Offsite-box 11)
    - CBS This Morning, CBS: "Four Season [sic] / Broadcasting", 1997 December 16 (Offsite-box 11)
    - John Francini, ABC, 1998 (Offsite-box 11)
    - Nick Drakides, CBS: "Public Eye", 1998 May 27 (Offsite-box 11)
    - David Letterman, CBS: "Martha Stewart Joke", 1998 July 20 (Offsite-box 11)
    - "Casino", 1998 November 6 (Offsite-box 11)
    - World News Tonight, ABC: "Alternative Dinner", 1998 November 25 (Offsite-box 11)
    - Charlie Rose / Four Seasons, 1999 June (Offsite-box 11)
    - NY1: Four Seasons, 1999 July 2 (Offsite-box 11)
    - CNN Pinnacle: The Four Seasons (2 copies), 2000 February 20 (Offsite-box 11)
    - NBC: Four Seasons, 2000 November 12 (Offsite-box 11)
    - 19.12.18 - 19.18.25, undated (Offsite-box 11)
    - Cholesterol Special, undated (Offsite-box 11)
    - Executive Chef Christian Albin, undated (Offsite-box 11)
    - Martha Stewart (Duck), undated (Offsite-box 11)
    - Talking Food Show #525, undated (Offsite-box 11)
    - labeled "Blank", undated (Offsite-box 11)
    - unlabeled, undated (Offsite-box 11)
  - Sub-series VI.B. CDs & DVDs (29 discs), 1999-2012, undated
    The digital media (i.e., CDs and DVDs) in Series VI, are currently restricted from access in order to ensure that the digital files are not accidentally corrupted. For further information please contact the curator of manuscripts at manuscripts@nyhistory.org.
    - CD. Four Seasons 50th Anniversary: Billy Farrell Bulk Selects (2 discs), 2009 June 11 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 12)
    - CD. Four Seasons 50th Anniversary: Patrick McMullan Bulk Selects (2 discs), 2009 June 11 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 13)
    - CD. Four Seasons 50th Anniversary: Neil Rasmus Bulk Selects (2 discs), 2009 June 11 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 14)
    - CD. Children's Day at the Four Seasons. Photos by Annie Watt, 2012 August 24 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 15)
    - CD. [Alex von Bidder, Julian Niccolini, Christian "Hitsch" Albin, Bill Clinton], undated (Offsite-box 7, Folder 16)
      Disc labeled "AVB / JN / HA / Clinton" holding one photo of Alex von Bidder (AVB), Bill Clinton, Four Seasons chef Christian "Hitsch" Albin (HA), and Julian Niccolini (JN).
    - CD. "All Photos", undated (Offsite-box 7, Folder 17)
    - DVD. Alex von Bidder and Julian Niccolini on Charlie Rose, 1999 June 29 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 18)
    - DVD. Rothko's Rooms: The Life and Works of an American Artist, 2000 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 19)
    - DVD. Darcy Miller, Wedding, [2001 May 5] (Offsite-box 7, Folder 20)
      The marriage of Darcy Miller, weddings editor at Martha Stewart Living magazine, to Andrew Nussbaum, took place at the Four Seasons on May 5, 2001.
    - DVD. Gourmet: Four Seasons Retrospective, 2003 March 31 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 21)
    - DVD. Colameco's Food Show: The Four Seasons, 2004 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 22)
    - DVD. Power Lunch at the Four Seasons (CNBC / NBC Universal) (2 copies), 2009 April 16 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 23)
    - DVD. Four Seasons Roast / PGP, [2009 May 5] (Offsite-box 7, Folder 24)
      Brief video prepared for the Four Seasons' 50th anniversary party on May 5, 2009. Features Le Cirque owner Sirio Maccioni.
    - DVD. The Ultimate Power Lunch: 50 Years at the Four Seasons (CNBC / NBC Universal) (5 copies), 2009 July 3 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 25)
    - DVD. Bethenny Getting Married?, season 1, episode 5 (4 copies), 2010 August 24 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 26)
      The marriage of Bravo TV reality start Bethenny Frankel to Jason Hoppy took place at the Four Seasons in March 2010. Footage of the ceremony and reception aired as season 1, episode 5 of the series "Bethenny Getting Married" (later renamed "Bethenny Ever After") on July 8, 2010. The date stamped on the DVD--August 24, 2010--is likely when the disc was burned.
    - DVD. [Bill White and Bryan Eure wedding] (3 copies), [2011 October 23] (Offsite-box 7, Folder 27)
      The marriage of Bill White and Bryan Eure took place at the Four Seasons on October 23, 2011.
    - DVD. [CNN story on Four Seasons], undated (Offsite-box 7, Folder 28)
- Series VII. Objects, 1995-2018, undated
  Larger-format plaques, awards, and restaurant rating signage. Includes construction samples from the Four Seasons second and final location, 42 East 49th Street.
  Organized chronologically.
  - New York Times plaque, 1995 March 17 (Offsite-box 13)
    Columnist Ruth Reichl's New York Times "Dining in New York" review of the Four Seasons, March 17, 1995, shellacked and mounted on a wooden plaque (19.5 x 12.5 inches).
    Caution
    Box is extremely heavy.
  - BiZBash award, 2005 (Offsite-box 12)
    Sculptural lucite, plastic, and metal letter "B" inscribed "Alex von Bidder / BiZBash Hall of Fame / 2005 BiZBash Event Style Awards."
  - Zagat rating (3 versions), 2014 (Offsite-box 12)
    Three Lucite plaques (2 large, 1 small) of the Four Seasons 2014 Zagat restaurant review rating, for which it received 27 (out of a possible 30) for food, 28 for decor, and 27 for service. Meals cost an average of $103 per person.
  - Hard hat, circa 2016-2018 (Offsite-box 12)
    White hard hat with Four Seasons logo and address 280 Park Avenue, the parent building of the restaurant's second and final location, 42 East 49th Street.
  - Stone & wood samples, circa 2016-2018 (Offsite-box 12)
    Two square (3 x 3-inch) stone tiles and three wood samples (marked "Four Seasons Rosewood," "Four Seasons Teak," and "Four Seasons Walnut,") presumably used in the restaurant's second and final location, 42 East 49th Street.
  - John Lewis Glass samples, circa 2016-2018 (Offsite-box 13)
    Two 8 x 8-inch samples of "cast glass goldleaf custom gold powder" for the bar counter in the Four Seasons second and final location, 42 East 49th Street.
  - Gift box with ribbon, undated (Offsite-box 12)
    Small (5 x 6.75-inch) hinged brown box with Four Seasons tree logo, plus white ribbon with same logo (inside box).